Now you will hear a speaker talking to a class on a trip to a marine aquarium.
Hello, everyone.
Thank you for visiting the aquarium today.
I hope you’ve enjoyed seeing the thousands of fish we have here, as well
as the other sea animals.
During the next hour we’re going to show you some more sea creatures.
They all come from a body of water called the Sargasso Sea.
The Sargasso Sea is actually part of the Atlantic Ocean.
What I mean is---it isn’t a separate body of water;
it’s more like a sea within an ocean.
It’s located off the southern half of North America,
and it is very large----it covers millions of kilometers.
Now, a couple of things make it distinctive.
First,
and probably most important, the waters there are very calm—calm and warm.
There’s also very little wind there.
Surrounding the Sargasso Sea are water currents in the Atlantic that move in a circular motion, counterclockwise.
This water swirls around the Sargasso Sea.
Because of the way these currents move, the water in the middle of the
Sargasso Sea doesn’t move much at all.
Because of the still waters and the lack of wind, sailing ships crossing the
Atlantic travel much more slowly when they get to the Sargasso Sea.
Without wind, sailboats can get stuck there for long periods.
Something else that’s unusual about the Sargasso Sea is the seaweed floating on its surface.
Large amounts of a kind of seaweed called sargassum float on top of the water there.
And because of the currents, the seaweed stays in the Sargasso Sea, it’s kind
of held in place by the rotating currents.
Now this seaweed is what interests us most here at the aquarium,
because it supports all kinds of sea life, like shrimp, crabs,
and fish.Sargassum creates an ecosystem for them to live in.Sargassum creates an ecosystem for
them to live in.
What makes this ecosystem quite remarkable is that the creatures there are one you’d
expect to find much closer to shore, much closer to land, not out in
the middle of the Atlantic Ocean.
Most likely, sargassum probably did not exist in the Sargasso originally.
Rather, the seaweed and some of the ecosystem it supported drifted out into the Sargasso Sea long ago
and became trapped there by the currents.
From there, it simply spread all over the Sargasso Sea.